<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>container security on Shelltrail - Swedish offensive security experts</title>
    <link>https://www.shelltrail.com/tags/container-security/</link>
    <description>Recent content in container security on Shelltrail - Swedish offensive security experts</description>
    <generator>Source Themes academia (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright &amp;copy; {year}</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="https://www.shelltrail.com/tags/container-security/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Kubernetes security assessment</title>
      <link>https://www.shelltrail.com/cyber-security-services/kubernetes-security-assessment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.shelltrail.com/cyber-security-services/kubernetes-security-assessment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Kubernetes is a commonly used container orchestration tool providing scalability
and resilience to enterprises utilizing containerized applications. Whether
it may be internal policies or for compliance reasons, it is always beneficial
to perform security assessments to proactively find vulnerabilities or
misconfigurations. This may lower probability of a compromise occurring, and
minimize the impact if it happens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-assessed-in-a-kubernetes-security-review&#34;&gt;What is assessed in a Kubernetes security review?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When doing a Kubernetes security review the initial perspective can vary, it
may be from the perspective of a compromised pod, a specific namespace or an employee with developer access.
From here publicly known attack paths will be evaluated in an attempt
to reach sensitive information or cluster-wide compromise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, CIS benchmarks will be used as a foundation for the assessment
making sure that industry standard best-practices is evaluated in the environment.
The Center for Internet Security (CIS) is a nonprofit organization that enhances
cybersecurity readiness and response across public and private sectors.
CIS provides extensive checklists in terms of best practices for security
configurations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;deliverables-after-conducting-a-security-review&#34;&gt;Deliverables after conducting a security review&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the end of the assessment a de-briefing meeting with key stakeholders will
be held to present the findings from the assessment, discuss recommendations and address
questions or concerns.
After the de-brief meeting the report will be delivered which includes an
assessment description, a results &amp;amp; recommendations section and an executive
summary. The executive summary is commonly used as a customer facing
report showing proactive work in the IT security realm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;contact&#34;&gt;Contact&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you wish to view a sample report or discuss/schedule an assessment,
please use our contact form or reach out to us via email at &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:info@shelltrail.com&#34;&gt;info@shelltrail.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
