<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Attack surface on Shelltrail - Swedish offensive security experts</title>
    <link>https://www.shelltrail.com/tags/attack-surface/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Attack surface on Shelltrail - Swedish offensive security experts</description>
    <generator>Source Themes academia (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright &amp;copy; {year}</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="https://www.shelltrail.com/tags/attack-surface/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>External infrastructure</title>
      <link>https://www.shelltrail.com/cyber-security-services/external-infrastructure/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.shelltrail.com/cyber-security-services/external-infrastructure/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When was the last time your company performed an inventory and review of all
internet-exposed systems? This is a good question to seek an answer to when you
want to assess the risk of your internet presence. Systems become obsolete, and
new vulnerabilities are discovered daily, which means companies must be diligent
in inventorying their systems, which ports are exposed, which versions of
different software are running, and map these against vulnerabilities that pose
a real threat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is a challenging task that must be iterated at regular basis and is not
always in line with the company&amp;rsquo;s prioritized goals. A common reason is a
&lt;em&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t fix it if it ain&amp;rsquo;t broken&lt;/em&gt; a attitude in combination with prioritization
of scale an growth which may leave internet-exposed system vulnerable to attacks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-does-a-pentest-of-external-infrastructure-entail&#34;&gt;What does a pentest of external infrastructure entail?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The assignment usually begins with the client providing a list of IP addresses and
domain names to be reviewed. In addition to this, Shelltrail uses Open Source
Intelligence sources (OSINT) to try to find more systems that may be undocumented
or classified as &lt;em&gt;Shadow IT&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once the list of identified systems is deemed complete, it is verified that all
targets are under the client&amp;rsquo;s security responsibility and not third-party
systems. If third-party systems are involved, written approval regarding the
security audit of the third-party must be submitted to Shelltrail&amp;rsquo;s security
consultants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With a complete list of legitimate targets, the testing begins where a
combination of automated and manual security audits of the systems is performed. Here,
techniques from all of Shelltrail&amp;rsquo;s areas of expertise are combined, such as
security reviews of web applications, Windows and Linux attacks, binary
exploitation, and cloud-specific attacks, to name a few.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shelltrail&amp;rsquo;s security experts possess a broad background in cybersecurity audits,
which serves well for the varied services that can be exposed on the internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-and-when-should-an-external-infrastructure-review-be-performed&#34;&gt;Why and when should an external infrastructure review be performed?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As previously mentioned, new vulnerabilities are discovered daily and systems
become End-of-Life, sometimes leading to the manufacturer ceasing to maintain
systems with security updates. This makes it important to periodically conduct a
review of internet-exposed systems to secure them before attackers find the system.
Regardless of whether your company produces garden hoses or develops pharmaceuticals,
your internet-exposed systems may become a target for opportunistic attackers
scanning the internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-result&#34;&gt;The Result&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The assignment results in a professional report where all security issues are described
in a detail. The vulnerabilities described in the report are ranked from
critical to low, and in combination with the client&amp;rsquo;s perceived risks, the report
can be used as a priority list in which order to address the problems. It is not
uncommon for the report to be used to increase the security budget for a company
or to inform, for example, management that security must be prioritized.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
