<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Privacy policy on Shelltrail - Experter inom offensiv säkerhet</title>
    <link>https://www.shelltrail.com/sv/privacy-policy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Privacy policy on Shelltrail - Experter inom offensiv säkerhet</description>
    <generator>Source Themes academia (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>sv-se</language>
    <copyright>Copyright &amp;copy; {year}</copyright>
    
	    <atom:link href="https://www.shelltrail.com/sv/privacy-policy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Shelltrail Privacy Policy</title>
      <link>https://www.shelltrail.com/sv/privacy-policy/privacy-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.shelltrail.com/sv/privacy-policy/privacy-policy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Shelltrail AB, org.no. 559319-6164 (hereinafter denoted &lt;strong&gt;Shelltrail&lt;/strong&gt;) is a
Swedish based cybersecurity company predominantly active in the offensive IT
security industry. This document is the privacy policy of Shelltrail, which
explains how our organization uses the personal data we collect, use, maintain
and disclose when you or the company you work for buys or uses the services we
provide or when you contact us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;topics&#34;&gt;Topics&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What data do we collect?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How do we collect your data?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How will we use your data?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How do we store your data?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Marketing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are your data protection rights?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How do we use cookies?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Privacy policies of other websites&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changes to our privacy policy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to contact us&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to contact the appropriate authorities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-data-do-we-collect&#34;&gt;What data do we collect?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shelltrail collects and processes data in order to be able to provide our
services to you. The data is either provided by you or your employer as part of
the delivery of a service, or as a means to contact you for future service
offerings. Shelltrail collects the following data:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When submitting data using our contact form&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identity information (name)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Contact information (email address)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;As part of the delivery of our services&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identity information (name, title, company)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Contact information (email address, telephone number)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-do-we-collect-your-data&#34;&gt;How do we collect your data?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The data is collected by Shelltrail in the following ways:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When submitting data using our contact form&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When submitting data using our contact form, the data is sent to a third-party
provider (Cloudflare), which generates an email.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;As part of the delivery of our services&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As part of the delivery of our services, you or your employer may supply contact
information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-will-we-use-your-data&#34;&gt;How will we use your data?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shelltrail collects the data in order to communicate with you regarding your
intention to get more information about our services or as part of an ongoing
assignment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shelltrail also uses the data to verify your identity and authority to
act on behalf of your employer or the organization you are representing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-do-we-store-your-data&#34;&gt;How do we store your data?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shelltrail stores data in the following ways, depending on the way it has been
retrieved:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When submitting data using our contact form&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When submitting data using our contact form, the data is sent to a third-party
provider (formspree.io), which generates an email. This email is stored in an
email inbox (gmail.com).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;As part of the delivery of our services&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The contact information supplied as part of the delivery of our services may
either be stored in an email inbox (gmail.com) or in an encrypted ephemeral
virtual machine, used solely for the purpose of the assessment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;marketing&#34;&gt;Marketing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shelltrail does not use the supplied information for marketing purposes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-are-your-data-protection-rights&#34;&gt;What are your data protection rights?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shelltrail would like to make sure you are fully aware of all of your data
protection rights. Every user is entitled to the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The right to access - You have the right to request Shelltrail for copies of
your personal data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The right to rectification - You have the right to request that Shelltrail
corrects any information you belive is inaccurate. You also have the right to
request Shelltrail to complete the information you belive is incomplete.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The right to erasure - You have the right to request that Shelltrail erase
your personal data, under certain conditions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The right to restrict processing - You have the right to object to
Shelltrail&amp;rsquo;s processing of your personal data, under certain conditions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The right to data portability - You have the right to request that Shelltrail
transfer all the data we have collected to another organization, or directly to
you, under certain circumstances.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you make a request, we have one month to respond to you. If you would like to
exercise any of these rights, please contact us at our email:
&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:privacy@shelltrail.com&#34;&gt;privacy@shelltrail.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-do-we-use-cookies&#34;&gt;How do we use cookies?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cookies are text files placed on your computer to collect standard Internet log
information and visitor behavior information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shelltrail does not make use of cookies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;privacy-policies-of-other-websites&#34;&gt;Privacy policies of other websites&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Shelltrail website may contain links to other websites. Our privacy policy
applies only to our website, so if you click on a link to another website, you
should stay informed of their privacy policy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;changes-to-our-privacy-policy&#34;&gt;Changes to our privacy policy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shelltrail keep its privacy policy under regular review and places any updates
on this web page. The privacy policy was last updated on 21 May 2024.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-contact-us&#34;&gt;How to contact us&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about Shelltrail&amp;rsquo;s privacy policy, the data we hold on
you, or you would like to exercise one of your data protection rights, please do
not hesitate to contact us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Email: &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:privacy@shelltrail.com&#34;&gt;privacy@shelltrail.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Address: Bredgatan 4, 21130, Malmö, Sweden&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-contact-the-appropriate-authority&#34;&gt;How to contact the appropriate authority&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Should you wish to report a complaint or if you feel that Shelltrail has not
addressed your concern in a satisfactory manner, you may contact the Swedish
Authority for Privacy Protection (IMY) &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.imy.se&#34;&gt;https://www.imy.se&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
