<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Red Team on Shelltrail - Swedish offensive security experts</title>
    <link>https://www.shelltrail.com/tags/red-team/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Red Team on Shelltrail - Swedish offensive security experts</description>
    <generator>Source Themes academia (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright &amp;copy; {year}</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="https://www.shelltrail.com/tags/red-team/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Red Team engagement</title>
      <link>https://www.shelltrail.com/cyber-security-services/red-team-engagement/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.shelltrail.com/cyber-security-services/red-team-engagement/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A Red Team-engagement is a simulated attack on an organization from a holistic
view that can include several different parts, such as phishing, social
engineering, attacks against externally exposed infrastructure as well as
internal systems. The simulation is intended to be similar to a real-world
attack, using the same Tools, Techniques and Procedures (TTPs) used by real
attackers (and often based on the specific threat actors of the targeted
business sector).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-a-red-team-engagement&#34;&gt;What is a Red Team engagement?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Red Team engagement are often confused with the closely related term penetration
testing, but differs greatly in a number of areas. While both deal with the
identification and exploitation of vulnerabilities they have different
methodology, goals, purpose and execution. While a pentest aims at identifying
as many vulnerabilities as possible in a network or system, a Red Team
engagement aim to assess an entire organizations resilience against a targeted
attack with one or more specific goals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal of a Red Team engagement can be, for instance to access specific
sensitive information, a certain mail account or the CEO&amp;rsquo;s user account in the
Active Directory domain. This often means that the attacker can act more
like a real threat, acting more stealthy as the goal is not to exploit
vulnerabilities that may trigger certain alarms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During a Red Team engagement it is also common to only notify a select group of
people that are aware the test is being conducted, so that the actions and
reactions from the staff more closely resembles what would happen in a
real-world scenario. By doing this, the organizational procedures can be
evaluated and improved upon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-and-when-should-a-red-team-engagement-be-conducted&#34;&gt;Why and when should a Red Team engagement be conducted?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is recommended to perform a Red Team engagement when the security posture of
the internal network is mature and tools and procedures are in place to handle
threats within the organization. As the aim is to evaluate how an entire
organization handles an attack, there is little need for evaluation if the
procedures are not in place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the network has undergone an internal assessment, identified
vulnerabilities fixed, procedures and monitoring are in place it would be a good
time to conduct a Red Team engagement to verify that everything works as
intended.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Besides these occasions, some regulatory frameworks such as Threat
Intelligence-based Ethical Red Teaming (TIBER) may require you to perform Red
Team exercises.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reporting-and-results&#34;&gt;Reporting and results&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reporting of a Red Team engagement differs from that of a normal pentest, as
the goals and approach to the test are different between the two test types. In
this type of test, the reporting is focused around what&amp;rsquo;s called an attack
narrative where the testers describes attacks performed, why the types of attack
were used, what the expected reactions from the defending team was and what
actually happened. As the goal is aimed at a specific target, all identified
vulnerabilities may not be included, but rather the path chosen by the attackers
at reaching the specified target. The report and de-briefing meeting also aims
to identify improvements that have an overall impact on both a technical as well
as on an organizational level.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
